Guide to the Thomas Michlovic Papers, 1978-2002 AIS.2002.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thomas Michlovic Papers
1978-2002
1987-2000
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Michlovic, Thomas A.
AIS.2002.04
33.8 Linear Feet (28 boxes)
The papers of Thomas A. Michlovic documents his career in the Pennsylvania House of Representatives (1977-2002). Materials are concentrated on the years between 1987 through 2001. The collection consists primarily of correspondence, campaign and election materials, legislative files, publications, photographs, and reports.
Biography
Thomas (Tom) A. Michlovic was born February 21, 1946 in Braddock, Pa. Michlovic served in the U.S. Army from 1967-1969. He received a B.A. in political science in 1972 and an M.A. in public administration in 1976, both from the University of Pittsburgh. In 1978 he was elected as a Democrat to the Pennsylvania House of Representatives for the 35th District. He remained in the House until his retirement in 2002. Since 2004 he has served on the Pennsylvania Securities Commission.
Arrangement
The original print finding aid, created by Kate Colligan and Trish Gillespie, sorted the collection into topical dividers. These divisions have been retained as subject sections for this finding aid.
Scope and Content Notes
Thomas A. Michlovic Papers document his career in the Pennsylvania House of Representatives 35th District, 1977-2002. The bulk of the collection (1987-2001) is comprised primarily of correspondence, legislative bills, campaign/election materials, and files related to the 35th District borough, cities, and townships. Subject areas of concentration include: healthcare in general but strongly focused on mental health, industry and labor, lobbyists, taxes, and transportation.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Thomas A. Michlovic Papers, 1978-2002, AIS.2002.04, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas A. Michlovic on September 26, 2002.
Legislation -- Pennsylvania; Legislators -- Pennsylvania; Allegheny County (Pa.) -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 1951-; Correspondence; Medical care -- Pennsylvania; Personal papers; Economic development projects -- Pennsylvania; Lobbyists -- Pennsylvania; Transportation -- Pennsylvania; Taxation -- Pennsylvania; Mental health services -- Pennsylvania; Political campaigns -- Pennsylvania; Labor -- Pennsylvania; Education -- Pennsylvania; Urban renewal -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Labor; Social action; Health and medicine; Politics; Pennsylvania. General Assembly. House of Representatives; Michlovic, Thomas A.
- City of Duquesne
  - General Files (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Strategy 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Duquesne City Center (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Thompson Run Bridge Rehabilitation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Duquesne/McKeesport Bridge Approach (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Duquesne Waterworks Place & Pension Fund Problem (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Duquesne Waterworks Place & Pension Fund Problem (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Duquesne Business Advisory Corporation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Duquesne Business Advisory Corporation Meeting Files, 1987-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
- City of McKeesport
  - General Files (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Application for Renziehausen Park - Regional Asset Distribution (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Center Street Railroad Crossing (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McKees Point Project (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sewer Backup - 10th Ward, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Envirotest Facility, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Enterprise Zone Program (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Metalized Paper Corporation (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 15th Street Bridge Project (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Quality Check Metals (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Integra Bank Building, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - McKeesport Carnegie Library (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Industry Road Project (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mon Valley Policy Committee - USX McKeesport/Duquesne Works Site
  - General Meeting Minutes, 1989-2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Project Status Reports (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Environmental Clean-up (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Engineer's Reports (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tennant List for Industrial Center of McKeesport and City Center of Duquesne (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bid Documents and Demolition Proposals (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Report for Mon Valley Industrial Sites, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Trafford, Swissvale, White Oak and Wall Borough
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- Wall Borough
  - Wall Water Facilities Project, Constituent Workshop and Wilmerding Consolidation (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
- Braddock Hills Borough
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 8)
- North Versailles Township
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Citizen Disputes (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Boyer Scandal (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Crestas Community Center (Box 3, Folder 12)
- North Braddock Borough
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sixth Street Project (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - North Braddock Cares - Community Developing Group (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 100th Anniversary (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Financial Recovery, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Wolfe Avenue Project (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lindberg Boulevard Project (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Tassey Hollow Sanitary Sewer Project (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Frazier Street Bridge (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Shady Park School Lot (Box 3, Folder 22)
- East Pittsburgh
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - East Pittsburgh Community Development Corporation (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Shamrock Square Townhouses Development (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Electric Avenue Flooding (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Turtle Creek Borough
  - General Files (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Flood Control, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dredging of Turtle Creek (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Flood Restoration Project (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Brown Avenue Realignment (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Turtle Creek Development Corporation (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Turtle Creek Centennial, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Saw Mill Run Creek Project and Brown Avenue Flooding (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Brown Avenue Property Damage (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Braddock Borough
  - General Braddock Files (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Braddock Economic Development Corporation (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Braddock Revitalization Development Corporation (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Brandywine Bar (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Braddock Parking Authority (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Riverfront Properties Braddock (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - S.H. Bell Soil Contamination (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Edgar Thompson - Mill Road (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Braddock Recovery Plan (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Braddock Audits (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Braddock Pollution Problem (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Braddock NAACP (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Braddock Law Enforcement - State Police (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Braddock Redevelopment Projects (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Rankin Borough
  - General Rankin Files (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Rankin Community Development Corporation (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fourth Street Waterline (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rankin Comprehensive Plan, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Rankin Bridge Project (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Vacant Property Acquisition (Box 4, Folder 20)
- American Wind Symphony Orchestra (AWSO)
  - AWSO History, By-Laws, Board of Directors (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting Minutes and Articles (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Winds on the Mon Education Program (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Regional Asset District Testimony, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - AWSO Tour Schedules (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Scotland School for Veterans' Children
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Crestas Terrace North Versailles, 1987-1988
  - 1988 Ceramic Kiln Project Proposal, Crestas Community Action Project to DECD, Michlovic letter of recommendation, County correspondence financial crisis (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic (WPIC), 1991
  - University of Pittsburgh Proposal for Merging WPIC to Presbyterian University Hospital (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Western Center
  - Michlovic Notes and Publicity (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1991-2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Aldo Giannini Case, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Mayview State Hospital
  - Democratic Policy Hearing Testimony, October, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- 1991 Woodville / Mayview State Hospital Merger
  - Preliminary Plan, Policy Position, Department Public Welfare Status Briefings, Allegheny County MH/MR Plan and Correspondence on Consolidation, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Budget Information MH/MR Funding, Correspondence and Publicity, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Woodville Project Michlovic Notes and Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Woodville Blue Ribbon Panel, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Unified System Mental Health Records, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Unified System MH/MR Funding, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Busway East
  - Michlovic Special Edition Report To The People, Correspondence, Michlovic Statement on the Issue – 1993 and Allegheny County Correspondence on the Issue, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Fort Pitt Bridge / Airport Busway / Wabash Tunnel
  - Colleague Correspondence, City of Pittsburgh Correspondence, General Correspondence and Riverlife Task Force Concrete Barriers, 1991-2001 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Rail Transit North Shore
  - Correspondence, Port Authority Publication North Shore Connector, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Medal of Honor Scholarship Fund
  - Functions, State Documents and Biographies (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Medal of Honor Highway
  - Amendments, Legislation, Dedication of the Highway and Michlovic's Press Release, 1999-2002 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Mon Valley Expressway
  - Meetings, Briefings and Michlovic's Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, Press Releases and Proposals (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Lobbyist Disclosure HB 2605, 1990
  - Bill Language and Michlovic's Press Release (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - State Government Hearing, August 14, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Background and Publicity (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Lobbyist Disclosure HB 551, 1991
  - Bill, analysis, Comparison to HB 2605 of 1009, Michlovic's Press Release and Statement and 1992 Amendment (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hearing February, 1992, Michlovic's Notes, Statement of Attorney General Preate, State Ethics Commission Statement, 1992 Non Profit Advocacy Network Panel, Northeastern Conference on Lobbying (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, Background and Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Lobbyist Disclosure HB 1376, 1993
  - Bill, Statement, Michlovic's Press Release, Notes and Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - State Government Hearing Michlovic's Statement, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Publicity and Background (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Lobbyist Disclosure HB 1946, SB 1180, SB 265, 1995-1996
  - HB 1946 Michlovic's Press Release and Statements – Colleague Correspondence; SB 1180 Senator Heckler's Bill, Correspondence and Press Advisory; SB 265 Senator Rhoades' Bill Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1996 Amendment to SB 1250, Michlovic's Notes; Amendment 3060 to HB 496 – Fiscal Note; Amendment 3059 to HB 1187 – Fiscal Note (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lobbyist Legislation Publicity and Background, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Lobbyist Disclosure, 1997-1998
  - HB 1498 Language, Recommended Amendments, Hearing and Michlovic's Testimony, July, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - SB 1 Language, Amendments, Analysis and Hearing, June, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - SB 254 – Act 93 of 1998 – Votes, Amendment and Michlovic's Notes (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, Michlovic/Colleague Correspondence and Common Cause Input (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Publicity and News Articles (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Lobbyist Disclosure, 1998-2000
  - Ethics Hearings and Michlovic's Press Release, December, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Court Challenge, Michlovic's Press Release and Correspondence, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Lobbyists
  - General Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Health Care Cost Containment Council HB 364 Recommendations, 1987
  - Press Release, Michlovic's Statement to HCCC, Michlovic's Correspondence, General Correspondence and Issue Information (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Mental Health/Mental Retardation Insurance HB 364, 1987
  - Bill, Amendments, Press Release, Michlovic's Statement, Micholvic Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reports HB 364 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Research Reports and Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Mental Health Trade Off Bill HB 1758, 1989
  - Bill, Analysis, Press Release, Michlovic's Press Statement and Correspondence, General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - HB 1758 Meetings and Michlovic's Notes (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hearing in Bethlehem, July 18, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hearing in Pittsburgh, August 16, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Background (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Mental Health Insurance HB 1448, 1991
  - Bill, Analysis, Michlovic's Notes and Meeting Notes (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence and Background (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Mental Health Insurance - Baltimore, MD Meeting, 1994
  - Meeting Notes (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Mental Health Parity HB 2237, 1995
  - Press Conference (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Insurance Hearing HB 2237, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Michlovic's Correspondence and General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Mental Health Parity HB 1286 / SB 887, 1997
  - Correspondence, Background, Press Conference and Michlovic's Remarks (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Gannon's Parity Amendment SB 875 - Act 29, 1997
  - Act, Amendment and Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Mental Health Proposals, 1997-1998
  - HB 1137 of 1997 / Amendment 4486 to SB 176 of 1997 / Amendment 2436 to SB 100 of 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Mental Health Parity HB 366 - Act 150, 1998-2001
  - Act 150, Michlovic's Correspondence 1997-1998, General Correspondence, LORL Report on Mental Health Care Parity, 2001 Representative DeLuca's Mental Health Parity Legislation and 2001 Legislative Budget & Finance Study on Act 150 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Plan B Stadium and Convention Center Funding, 1997-1999
  - Correspondence, Thank You, Letters of Support and Opposition (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - HB 2937-2939 / HB 2941-2943 / HB 553 / HR 554 of 1999 – SB 10 Bills, Amendments, Summary Sheets, Fact Sheets, Commentary and Statistics, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - HB 907 of 1998 – Governor's Veto, News Articles, Legal Opinion by Local Government Commission and Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Gas Tax, 1997
  - HB 67 Votes, Amendment 1473, Analysis and Fiscal Note (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Talking Points After Vote, Thank You, Support Letters, and Statistics (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Regional Renaissance - 1/2 Cent Sales Tax, 1997-1998
  - Proposals – SB 125, Amendments and Votes HB 1600 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Issue Papers, Commentaries, Publicity and Meeting Notices (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Compac 21 Home Rule Charter, 1997-1998
  - HB 329 Bill and Votes / Final Revision (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Proposals, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lehigh County Home Rule Charter (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Senator Bodack Release, Levdansky's Information mailed to supporters and elected officials in opposition to Home Rule, Michlovic's Remarks, Senator Bodack's Opinion Column to Pittsburgh Newspapers and Statement and WTAE Editorial Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Hotel Tax, 1993
  - Preliminary Investigation – 1992, Schedule of Hotel Room Rental Tax Receipts – 1993, List of Organizations Receiving Revenue, Distribution Chart, Correspondence and Report to Allegheny County Delegation, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Regional Asset District (RAD)
  - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - HB 659 of 1993 – Proposals, Fact Sheets, Statistics, Summaries (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Michlovic's Notes, Debate, Testimony, News Articles and Vote on HB 659 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Report on Tax Base Sharing, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - News Releases, Correspondence and Board Members, 1997-2001 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Local Tax Reform, 1993
  - Local Government Conference Consensus Paper, Questionnaire and Survey Results. Proposal and Summary of Bill (Box 8, Folder 19)
- 1% Sales Tax - Local Optional Tax, 1991-1992
  - Debate Amendment 4359 to SB 792, Amendment 4202, SB 792 and Vote (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence – SB 692 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Articles (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - SB692 language, Statistics and Vote (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Pennsylvania League of Cities, Speech and Notes (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Occupational Tax, 1990
  - Correspondence to Support Increase/Lowering of the Amusement Tax, Mayor Murphy's Memo to Delegation, Pittsburgh Press Articles and Chart of districts (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Mental Health Drug and Alcohol Insurance Coverage HB 665, 1981
  - Michlovic's Correspondence, Press Releases and Personal Notes (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Michlovic's Testimony at Hearing, December, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - HB 665 Language and Background (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Compromise HB 665 and 1890, Language and Michlovic's Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Meetings Related to HB 665, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Organizations, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Publicity (Box 9, Folder 7)
- MH/MR Drug and Alcohol Insurance Coverage HB 1132, 1993
  - Bill, Language, Amendment, SB 832 and Michlovic's Notes (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Press Conference, Michlovic's Statement, Press Release (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Michlovic's Correspondence and General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - MH/MR Publicity (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - ADM Coalition (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Public Hearing, August, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Research and Background (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Insurance Committee Meeting of April, 1984 and Amendments (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Alcohol Insurance Coverage HB 1901, 1984
  - Bill, Analysis, Amendments, Votes, Correspondence and Notes (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Insurance Committee Meeting (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Insurance Committee Hearing (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Benefits for Treating Mental Disorders SB 936, 1985
  - Bill, Analysis, Vote and Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Amending Insurance Company Law, 1985-1986
  - Drafts and Background Information (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Unfair Insurance Practices Act HB 2161, 1986
  - Bill, Michlovic's Press Conference, Statement, Correspondence and Publicity (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Mon Valley Education Consortium
  - Mission Statement (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - General (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Leadership Retreat, April 5, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "The Future is Mine" Program (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Early Childhood Education
  - Gateways Pittsburgh (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Education
  - School Funding Equity (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Making The Grade In Pennsylvania (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - PA School Performance Incentive Grant Program (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Allegheny East School To Career Connection (Box 10, Folder 9)
- School Districts in the 35th Legislative District
  - McKeesport School District (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Duquesne School District (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Duquesne High School Basketball Team Champions – Day in Harrisburg (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Duquesne School District Commonwealth Audit 1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Duquesne School District Federal Chapter 1 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Duquesne School District Split Schedule Dispute (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Duquesne School Library (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - East Allegheny School District (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - E.A. School District DER Report on the Green Valley School (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - East Allegheny School District Commonwealth Audit, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - General Braddock School District (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - General Braddock School District – Al Berton Case (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - General Braddock School District – Desegregation Case (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Woodland Hills School District (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Report of Woodland Hills Ad-hoc Committee for Long Range Planning (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Woodland Hills School District Report & Recommendations Regarding Desegregation Remedies (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Woodland Hills School District Commonwealth Audit, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Woodland Hills School District Special Education Subsidies, 1995-2000 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Woodland Hills Task Force on Youth Violence (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Woodland Hills School District Tax Abatement (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Job Training Education Initiative Package (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Council of Governments (COG)
  - Turtle Creek COG By-laws (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Turtle Creek Valley COG – General (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Steel Valley and Twin Rivers COG (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Millsites and Steel Industry/Historical Designations
  - Steel Retention - Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State Conference On Steel Meeting Minutes (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Westinghouse Electric Relocation of Switchgear Manufacturing (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Keystone Commons (Formerly Westinghouse Electric) Meeting Minutes (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Keystone Commons – The Conrad Project, Broadcasting Museum (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Visit, February 1, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Homestead Mill Site Development Task Force (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Homestead Works and Carrie Furnace Sites (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - LTV South Side Works – Buy Out Committee (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - McKeesport / Duquesne RIDC Sites (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Edgar Thompson Plant Continuous Caster (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Steel Valley Regional Planning Commission (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Steel – "Community Capitalism" (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh History and Landmark Foundation – Steel Mills (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Growth Alliance (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Industrial Resource Centers – SPIRC (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - East Pittsburgh Historical District (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Historically Designated Properties in Braddock & East Pittsburgh (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - PA History & Museum Commission Study of Mon/Fayette Transportation Project, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Westinghouse Museum – Wilmerding (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Homestead Planning Commission (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Homestead Centennial Symposium, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Braddock Medical Center and Heritage Health Systems
  - Braddock Medical Center Mission Statement and By-Laws (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Braddock Hospital Proposal, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Braddock Medical Center Board Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Braddock Medical Center & Health Heritage systems Partnership Audit, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Braddock Medical Center & Health Heritage Systems Board Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Braddock Medical Center & Health Heritage Systems Board Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Braddock Medical Center & Health Heritage Systems Board Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Braddock Medical Center Agreement with UPMC, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Heritage Health Foundation Board Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - UPMC – Braddock Managed Healthcare (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Heritage Health Foundation Community Transportation Group (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Braddock Medical Center Articles of Incorporation (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Hospitals in Distressed Municipalities
  - General Information (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Healthcare Reform, 1994
  - Healthcare Reform (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Testimony on Healthcare Reform Given to US Senator Harris Wofford, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Valley Community Management Corporation
  - General Information (Box 12, Folder 16)
- The Jewish Healthcare Foundation of Pittsburgh
  - General Information (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Blue Cross/Blue Shield
  - General Information (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Food to Grow
  - General Information (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Greater Pittsburgh Convention and Visitors Bureau
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Golf Classic, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)